Yogesh Kumar Mahawar

Date of Birth: 11th august 1993 | Gender: Male | Nationality: Indian Pune, Maharashtra | Email Address: yogeshmahawar93@gmail.com | +917083684995

OBJECTIVE

To work in association with professional groups who offer me the opportunity for career advancement and professional growth. I possess one year of strong experience in field.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

System Engineer at Infosys Technologies Limited, Pune

Time Period: November 2015- current

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Work directly at client end in distributed development environment
- Develop microservices to centralize end web services at single platform
- Develop microservices and enhance existing payment solution for client
- Develop microservices to enhance existing Application Management System
- Exposing web services through API Management System
- Test and deploy microservices
- Develop responsive web user interface
- Development and Production support for all tech Issues

Technology Used: Nodejs, MongoDB, SpringMVC, Maven, Apigee, JSP, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, HTML, JSON, Bamboo, Jira, docker

Achivements: 2 times nominated for quarterly and half yearly award inside unit (3200 employee)

System Engineer trainee at Infosys Technologies Limited, Mysore

Time Period: June 2015- October 2015

Roles & Responsibilities: Learn and get expertise in various technologies

EDUCATION

•	Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science	2015	C.G.P.A.: 7.62
	National Institute of Technology, Raipur (C.G.)		
•	Class XII	2010	86.15 %
	Rajasthan Board of Secondary Education		
	Shahid Satyavir Singh Govt. S. S. School, Gadoli		
•	Class X	2008	88.33 %
	Raiasthan Board of Secondary Education		

Rajasthan Board of Secondary Education Adarsh Public School, Nadbai

SKILLS / EXPERTIES

Programming Language:
C, C++, J2SE, J2EE, TypeScript, Python

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, JSP, Angular 2.0, NodeJs

Web Service Architecture: MVC (Spring MVC, Restify, Express)

Web API Management Tool:
Apigee Edge (Google)

Database Management System: MySQL, Oracle Express 10g, MongoDB

Programming Environment:
Eclipse, Intellij, codeblocks, Atom, Visual Studio Code

Version Control System: Git, SVN

PROJECTS

Title	Duration	Skills Practiced	Team	Role
Secure Outsourcing of scientific computation over cloud	January 2015- May 2015	JAVA, Cloud computing, Sockets	4	Implement security solution to computation at unreliable cloud
College Festival website	July 2015 –	HTML, JavaScript,	3-4	Developer
	March 2016	Jquery, MySQL		
Image Sharing website	Jan 2014 – May	HTML, JavaScript,	3	Developer
	2014	Jquery, MySQL		

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Playing Synthesizer
- Painting
- Photography

DECLARATION

Place:	
Date:	Yogesh Kumar Mahawar

I hereby declare that all the details mentioned above are true to my knowledge and belief.